ListView starts by requesting a view for every visible item, however many you
can fit onto the screen. It'll also create a couple in either direction to make
sure we can scroll without seeing a flicker as a new view is created and
populated. Then it creates new items just in time. So it's next in line to
be visible to the user. So if the user never scrolls to the bottom of the list,
the ListView will never request that view from the adapter. But this is really
just a half measure. As you can see, if the user keeps scrolling, we could
potentially just keep adding new views, even if they disappear off the top of
the screen. Eventually that's going to lead to the same impact in memory use and
performance as if we had just created all of these views directly at
the beginning. The solution is recycling each view as it scrolls off the screen,
allowing it to be reused when we need to show another item as it
moves into view at the top or bottom. So rather than having to create and
then hold in memory each item of the list as it comes in to view,
we only need to do the creation step for the number of visible items and
couple on either side. Then whenever a new list item comes into view,
we just update the data displayed in one of our items in our recycle bin.
The result? Less memory overhead, smoother scrolling and
less view management you have to do yourself. This same recycling behavior is
implemented across all AdapterView descended classes, such as GridView and
ListView, which also introduces the reason that the adapter isn't built
directly into these controls themself. By keeping them separate,
your adapter defines how to display each element of the underlying data,
while the adapter view implementation itself is responsible for
controlling how each of these elements is laid out. Be it a list or
a grid in these particular instances.